<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iconomix | Brendan Berthold</title>
    <link>/category/iconomix/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/iconomix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>iconomix</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© All Rights Reserved 2021 - Brendan Berthold </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua848e79448441ec6a0fd16527faeebba_18289_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>iconomix</title>
      <link>/category/iconomix/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iconomix : payment methods in Switzerland</title>
      <link>/post/iconomix-payment-methods-in-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/iconomix-payment-methods-in-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parallel to my PhD studies, I work as an economic specialist for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iconomix.ch/fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iconomix&lt;/a&gt;, the education platform of the Swiss National Bank. In particular, I regularly write educational content about economics aimed at secondary schools and beyond in Switzerland. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.iconomix.ch/videos/fr_v04-02/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;In this post&lt;/a&gt;, we talk about the different payment methods in Switzerland. In particular, I document several trends about their relative utilization and how it compares internationally. I also talk about Kenneth Rogoff&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;The Curse of Cash&amp;rdquo;. Finally, I argue that even though cash is less used than before, it is still appreciated by the Swiss population, and is thus unlikely to disappear entirely in the near future. The article is in French.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iconomix : the concept of offer and demand</title>
      <link>/post/iconomix-the-concept-of-offer-and-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/iconomix-the-concept-of-offer-and-demand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parallel to my PhD studies, I work as an economic specialist for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iconomix.ch/fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iconomix&lt;/a&gt;, the education platform of the Swiss National Bank. In particular, I regularly write educational content about economics aimed at secondary schools and beyond in Switzerland. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.iconomix.ch/videos/fr_v07/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;In this post&lt;/a&gt;, we talk about the concept of offer and demand and how they interact in order to reach an equilibrium. I also give some practical real-world examples to highlight that the law of offer and demand is grounded in reality and is not merely theoretical. Any comments or remarks are warmly welcome. The article is in French.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
